A Guide to the Frank H. Field papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA160
Rockefeller Archive Center
Frank H. Field papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1946-2014
Rockefeller Archive Center
Field, F. H. (Frank Henry)
FA160
9.88 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
Frank H. Field (1922- ), Camille and Henry Dryfus Professor at the Rockefeller University, headed the laboratory of physical chemistry and mass spectrometry. Dr. Field was a leader in the field of mass spectrometry and the study of reactions, energetics, and kinetics of gaseous ions.
Starting in 1972, with funds from the. National Institutes of Health, his laboratory provided mass spectrometry services to biomedical workers and institutions in the New York metropolitan area.
In his early work in the petroleum industry, Dr. Field helped advance the analysis of materials of potential economic significance through the use of low-voltage mass spectrometry and chemical ionization mass spectrometry.
Dr. Field received his B.S. (1943), M.S. (1944) and Ph. D. (1948) degrees in chemistry from Duke University. From 1952-1962, he worked with the Humble Oil and Refining Co. and the Esso Research and Development Company. During 1963-1964, Dr. Field was a John Guggenheim Fellow at the University of Leeds. He received a faculty appointment at the Rockefeller University in 1970 and became Dryfus professor in 1988. Dr. Frank H. Field retired in 1989.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondents include Wilbur Burnaby, Hyp J. Dauben, Jr., Vernon Dibeler, William Doering, A.A. Draeger, Mark G. Inghram, Frederick W. Lampe, W.F. Libby, Einar Lindholm, F.P. Lossing, Fred L. Mohler, R.S. Mullikan, R.I. Reed, and Henry M. Rosenstock.
Subjects include chemical ioniation mass spectrometry, gaseous anion chemistry, Humble Oil, reversible reactions of gaseous ions, reaction kinetics, reactions of gaseous ions, and peptide sequencing.
Arrangement note
Arranged in 5 series:
Series 1: Reprints, 1946-1988. Series 2: Manuscripts, 1966-1980. Series 3: Correspondence, 1952-1964. Series 4: Photographs Series 5: Accession 2014:036, 1943-2014.
Within series records are primarily arranged in chronological and in alphabetical order.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 F454
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Cell and biomolecular sciences; Chemistry; Biochemistry; Mass spectrometry; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University
- Reprints, 1946-1988; 1; 1.32 Cubic Feet
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - The Vapor Pressures of Some Orqanic Fluorides, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 68 (1946): 2649-2650, 1946 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Absorption Spectra of Certain Nickel (II) and... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 72 (1950): 4232-4235, 1950 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Ionization Potential of Cyclopropane... J. of Chem. Phys., 18 (1950): 1122-1123, 1950 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A New Calculation of the Latent Heat of... J. of Chem Phys., 19, no. 6 (1951): 793, 1951 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Dissociation of Cyclopropane Under Electron Impact, J. of Chem. Phys., 20,no. 11 (1952): 1734-1739, 1952 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Resonance Energies of Certain Organic Free Radicals and Ions, J. of Am. Chem Soc., 75 (1953): 2819, 1952 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Electron Impact Studies of the Vinyl Ion and Radical, J. of Chem. Phys., 21 (1953): 1506-1510, 1952 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Energies of Strained Carbonium Ions, J. of Chem. Phys., 21, no. 3 (1953): 550-551, 1953 January 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Some Aspects of the Dissociation of Benzene... J. of Chem. Phys., 21, no. 11 (1953): 2082-2083, 1953 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Electron Impact Studies of Some... J. of Chem. Phys., 22, no. 11 (1954): 1895-1904, 1953 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Ionization Potentials of... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 76 (1954): 1994-1997, 1953 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gas Phase Ionic Reactions, Methane and Ethylene, J. of Am, Chem. Soc., 78 (1956): 5697, 1956 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Reactions of Gaseous Ions. I. Methane... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 79 (1957): 2419-2429, 1956 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Determination of Unsaturated Hydrocarbons by... Analy. Chem., 28 (1956).-1248-1255 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reactions of Gaseous Ions. (RGI) II. Acetylene, J. of Am. Chem. Soc, 79 (1957): 2665-2669, 1957 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cross Sections for Ionization by Electrons, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 79 (1957): 6129-6132, 1957 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - RGI. IV. Water, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 79 (1957): 6132-6135, 1957 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - RGI. III. Formation of Protonated Methane, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 79 (1957): 4244, 1957 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - RGI. V. Methane-Hydrogen Chloride... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 80 (1958): 5583-5586, 1958 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - RGI. VI. Hydride Ion Transfer Reactions, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 80 (1958): 5587-5592, 1958 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Decomposition of Neopentane... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 81 (1959): 3238-3241, 1958 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Addition of Ethyl Radicals to Ethylene, Canadian J. of Chem., 37 (1959): 995-998, 1958 December 29 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - RGI. VII. Methane-Hydrogen and the... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 81 (1959): 3242-3244, 1959 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Reactions of Ions with Molecules in... Tetrahedron 7, nos. 3/4 (1959): 189-205, 1959 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Russian Paper on CH5+, 33, no. 3 (1959): 732-733 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - RGI. VIII. Multiple Order Ion. Molecule... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 83 (1961): 1523-1534, 1960 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - RGI. X. Ionic Reactions in Xenon-Methane Mixtures, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 83 (1961): 4509-4513, 1961 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - RGI. XI. Ionic Reactions in Krypton... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 84 (1962): 1118-1122, 1961 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Rare-Gas Molecule-Ion Formation by... J. of Chem. Phys., 36, no. 12 (1962): 3332-3344, 1961 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Mass Spectrometer Reveals Inert Gas Ions, Chem. and Eng. News., 39 (1961): 32-33, 1961 December 25 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Kinetics of the Reactions of... Progress in Reaction Kinetics 1 (1961): 69 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - High-Pressure Mass Spect. Study of... J. of Chem. Phys., 37, no. 8 (1962): 1790-1799, 1962 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - A Mass Spect. Study of Homonuclear... J. of Phy. Chem., 67 (1963): 1542-1548, 1963 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - RGI. XII. Hiqh Pressure Mass Spect., Study of... J. of Am. Chem., Soc., 85 (1963): 3575-3583, 1963 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - RGI. CIII. The System Methane-Hydroqen. J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 85 (1963): 3584-3588, 1963 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Benzene Production in the Radiation... J. of Phys. Chem., 68 (1964): 1039-1047, 1963 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - A High Pressure Mass Spect. Study of... Advances in Mass Spect., 3 (1964): 359-375, 1964 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - High Pressure Mass Spectrometric Study... J. of Phys. Chem., 68 (1964): 3098-3107, 1964 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ionic Reactions and Radiolysis of CH4, J. of Chem. Phys., 42, no. l (1965): 442-443, 1964 August 3 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - RGI. XIV. Mass Spect. Studies of Methane... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 87 (1965): 3289-3294, 1965 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - RGI. XV. Methane + 1% Ethane... J. of Am. Chem Soc, 87 (1965): 3294-3299, 1965 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - RGI. XVI. Effects of Additives on Ionic... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 87 (1965): 4242-4247, 1965 May 21 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Chemical Ionization Mass Spectrometry. (CIMS) I. General Information, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 88 (1966): 2621-2630, 1966 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - CIMS. II. Esters, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 88 (1966): 4337-4345, 1966 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Mass Spect. Investigations of Gaseous... Presentation given at 31st Midyear Meeting of the Am. Petroleum Institute's Division of Refining, no. 27-66 (1966] 1: 1-6, 1966 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - CIMS. Paraffin Hydrocarbons, Advances in Chemistry Series., 58 (1966): 167-192 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - CIMS. VI. C7H8 Isomers... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 89 (1967): 5328-5334, 1967 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - CIMS. V. Cycloparaffins, J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 89 (1967): 4272-4280, 1967 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - CIMS. VII. Reactions of Benzene Ions with Benzene, J. of Am. Chem. Soc, 89: 24 (1967): 6036-6038, 1967 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - CIMS. Accounts of Chem. Research... Accounts of Chem. Res., 1 (1968): 42, 1967 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Advances in Mass Spectrometry, Adlard & Son Ltd., 4 (1967): 6456, 1967 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Chemical Ionization Mass Spectrometry (CIMS). VIII. Alkenes and Alkynes, J. of Am. Chec., Soc., 90 (1968): 5649-5656, 1968 March 16 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - CIMS. IX. Temperature and Pressure Studies... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 91 (1969): 2827-2839, 1968 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Effect of Temperature on... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 91 (1969): 2839-2842, 1968 October 26 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Reactions of Gaseous Ions (RGI). XVII. Methane +... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 91 (1969): 3413-3418, 1968 December 23 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - CIMS of Complex Molecules III. The Structure... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 92 (1970): 1597-1600, 1969 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - CIMS XI. Reactions of Methoxymethyl... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 92 (1970): 1600-1605, 1969 August 11 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - CIMS XIII. Reactions of Methyltheomethyl... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 92 (1970): 6521-6525, 1970 January 15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - CIMS XIII. Alcohols... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 92 (1970): 2672-2676, 1970 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reversible Reactions of Gaseous Ions (RRGI). III. Studies with Methane... 93 (1971): 1585-1591, 1970 July 8 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - RRGI. II. Propane-Water System... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 93 (1971): 1576-1584, 1970 July 8 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - CIMS. Temperature Effects in Tertiary... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 94 (1972): 2913-2919, 1971 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Investigation of Polytertiary Alkylam... Anal. Chem., 43 (1971): 1048-1052, 1971 March 3 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - RRGI. IV. Further Studies on the Equilibrium... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 94 (1972): 5186-5188, 1971 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - CIMS. XVIII. Effect of Acid Identity on... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 94 (1972): 3359-3360, 1971 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - RRGI. V. The Methane-Water System... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 94 (1972): 5188-5195, 1972 January 5 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - CIMS. XVII. Effect of Pressure on the... J. of Phys Chem., 76 (1972): 3917-3919, 1972 February 17 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - RRGI. VI. The NH3-CH4... J. of Am. Chem Soc., 94 (1972): 6305-6310, 1972 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - RRGI. VII. The Hydroqen System... J. of Am. Chem. Soc, 94 (1972): 8669-8672, 1972 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ion-Molecule Reactions in Ethane... J. of Phys. Chem., 76 (1972): 3919-3926, 1972 July 20 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - CIMS. XIV. Temperature Studies of... J. of Org. Chem., 38 (1973): 3380-3382, 1972 September 19 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Determination of Nitrogen-15 by CIMS, Anal. Chem., 45, no. 7 (1973): 1288-1290, 1972 November 30 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ion-Clustering of the Cations in the... Radiation Research, 56, no. 3 (1973): 441-459, 1973 May 7 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - CIMS. XIX, n-Hexane and... Org. Mass Spect., 8 (1974): 267-277, 1973 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CIMS. XX. Energy Effects and Virtual Ion... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 95 (1973): 7207-7211, 1973 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - CIMS. XXI. Reactions in t-C5... J. of A. Chem. Soc., 96 (1974): 359-364, 1973 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Isobutane Chemical Ionization Mass Spect... Int. J. Peptide Protein Res., 5 (1973) 435-446, 1973 July 4 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - RRGI. VIII. The t-CH9+... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 95 (1973): 4483-4486, 1973 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - CIMS. i-Butane Reactant Gas... Org. Mass Spect., 9 (1974): 195-203, 1973 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Association and Solvation Reactions of... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 96 (1974): 3168-3171, 1973 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Indications of Stereospecific Loss of Water... J. of Org. Chem., 39 (1974): 1752-1753, 1974 January 19 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Kinetics, Equilibrium and Neqative Temperature... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 96 (1974): 3727-3732 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Kinetics and Thermodynamics of... J. of Chem. Phys., 61, no. 9 (1974): 3742-3749, 1974 June 5 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - RRGI. IX. The Stability of C4-C7... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 97 (1975): 2625-2628, 1974 June 25 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - A Comparative Study of Cytokinesins I and... Proceedings of the NAS, 71, no. 10 (1974): 4140-4143, 1974 July 29 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - The Temperature Dependences of Some... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 97 (1975): 2014-2017, 1974 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Benzyl Alcohol: High Levels Found in... Clinica Chemica Acta, 61 (1975): 399-401, 1974 August 9 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - On the Negative Temperature Dependence of... J. of Phys. Chem., 78 (1974): 1773-l774 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Decomposition Rates of Excited Reaction... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 97 (1975): 5339-5345, 1975 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Chem. Mass Markers in Chem. Ionization, Anal. Chem., 47 (1975): 2289-2292, 1975 April 28 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - C-Methylation: An Artifact in Peptides... Biomed. Mass Spect., 2 (1975): 254-260, 1975 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - CIMS of Quaternary Amines, Biomed. Mass Spect., 2 (1975): 164-167, 1975 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - RRGI. X. The Intrinsic Stability of... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 98 (1976): 1567-1569, 1975 June 20 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Loss of Water from Ketones in... J. of Org. Chem., 41 (1976): 136-141, 1975 July 1 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Thermal Transitions between Collisionally and... J. of Chem. Phys., 64, no. 1 (1976): 277-281, 1975 August 21 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Dimethyl Disulfide: An Attractant... Science, 191 (1976): 948-950, 1975 October 20 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Stability of Some C7 Tertiary... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 98 (1976): 1025-1026, 1975 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Unimolecular Thermal Decomposition... J. of Phys. Chem., 80 (1976): 2865-2869, 1976 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Thermodynamic Ionization Energies and... Chem. Phys. Letters., 44, no. 3 (1976): 484-489, 1976 April 6 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Detection System for Negative Ions in... Anal. Chem., 48 (1976): 2042-2044, 1976 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Stability, Association and Dissociation in the... J. of Am. Chem Soc, 99 (1977): 998-1003, 1976 July 7 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Peptide Sequencing: The Utility of Chemical... Biomed. Mass Spect. 4, no. 3 (1977): 159-171, 1976 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Rotational Isomerism in Leucine: Proton... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 99 (1977): 2953-2957, 1976 August 16 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Proton Affinities and Cluster... J. of Chem. Phys., 66, no. 10 (1977). 4527-4531, 1976 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Drug Interactions with Methadone, Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 281 (1976): 350-370, 1976 December 10 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Thermal and Nonthermal Decompositions... J. of Am. Chem Soc., 99 (1977): 5576-5583, 1977 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Reference Lineshape Adjusted Difference NMR... J. of Magnetic Resonance, 28 (1977): 93-104, 1977 February 8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correlation between Exothermicity Rate and... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 100 (1978): 1356-1359, 1977 March 22 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hepatic Extraction of Long-and Short-Acting... Gastroenterology, 75 (1978): 88-94, 1977 April 11 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gaseous Anion Chem. Formation and... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 99, no. 10 (1977): 6471-6483, 1977 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bonding Energies in Assoc. Ions of... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 100 (1978). 5466-5471, 1978 January 10 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - [OH] - Negative CIMS... Biomed. Mass Spect., 5, no. 10 (1978): 572-575, 1978 January 24 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ion Thermochemistry of Low-Volatility Compounds... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 101 (1979): 686-689, 1978 July 18 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hydroxyl Ion Negative CIMS... Anal. Chem., 51 (1979): 272-178, 1978 August 4 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Isotope Exchange Reactions of OH- or OD- with... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 102 (1980): 4672-4676, 1979 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gaseous Anion Chemistry. Negative Chem. Ionization of... J. of Org. Chem., 45 (1980). 1614-1619, 1979 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Effects of Liver Disease on Urinary Excretion... Biomed. Mass Spect., 7, no. 9 (1980): 385-395, 1980 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - CIMS of L-Methionine and... Biomed. Mass Spect., 8, no. 3 (1981): 95-98, 1980 March 27 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Internal and External Solvation of Polyfunctional... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 102 (1980): 6393-6399, 1980 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Gaseous Anion Chemistry. Hydrogen-Deuterium... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 45 (1980): 3483-3492, 1980 May 6 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - High-Performance Digital Timing System, Anal. Chem., 52 (1980): 1923-1928, 1980 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Analysis of Lithium Using a... Biomed. Mass Spect., 8, no. 1 (1981): 19-24, 1980 July 29 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Fission Fragment Ionization... Int. J. of Mass Spect. and Ion Physics., 39 (1981): 339-366, 1980 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cholest-5-ene-3B, 26-diol: Synthesis... Biomed. Mass Spect., 9, no. 2 (1982): 61-63, 1981 January 14 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Comparison of Mass Spectra Obtained with... Anal. Chem., 53 (1981): 1241-1244, 1981 March 2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fission Fragment Ionization Mass Spect... Int. J. of Mass Spect. and Ion Phys., 41 (1981): 17-29, 1981 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fission Fragment Ionization Mass Spect... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 104 (1982): 5157-5162, 1981 September 28 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 252 Cf Fission Fragment Ionization Mass... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 104 (1982): 5519-5521, 1982 May 24 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Fast Atom Bombardment Study of Glycerol... J. of Phys. Chem., 86 (1982): 5115-5123, 1982 June 18 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Effects of Liver Disease on Fecal Excretion of... Biomed. Mass Spect., 10, no. 10 (1983): 544-549, 1982 July 16 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Determination of Total Body Water by... Biomed. Mass Spect., 10, no. 11 (1983): 596-600, 1982 August 16 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 252 Df Fission Fragment Ionization Mass... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 106 (1984): 1931-1938, 1983 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Fission Fragment Ionization Mass Spect... Int. J. of Mass Spect. and Ion Processes, 58 (1984): 121-137, 1983 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Short Communication. Structures of Metabolites... Drug Metabolism and Disposition, 12, no. 6 (1984): 784-786, 1983 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Pole Bias Scanner for Quadrupole... Anal. Chem., 57 (1985): 1165-1167, 1984 October 24 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Androsterone Long Chain. Fatty Acid... J. of Clin. Endocrin. and Metabolism, 60, no. 5 (1985): 940-946, 1984 October 24 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - A Study of the Metastable Fragmentation of... Int. J. of Mass Spect. and Ion Processes, 65 (1985): 169-180, 1984 November 21 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Identification of 19-Nor-Corticosterone in Rat Urine, Steroids, 45, no. 1 (Jan 1985): 91-98, 1985 January (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Mass Spect. of Microscale Chemical Reaction... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 107 (1985): 6743-6744, 1985 April 1 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Mass Spect. in Chem., Biomed. Mass Spect., 12, no. 10 (1985): 626-630, 1985 April 23 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Electron, Chemical and Thermal Ionization... Anal. Chem., 54 (1986): 679-684, 1985 July 29 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Reduction in Liquid Secondary Ion Mass... Anal. Chem., 58 (1986): 1070-1076, 1985 August 12 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Particle Bombardment (FAB) Mass Spect of... J. of Am. Chem. Soc., 108 (1986): 3897-3903, 1985 November 25 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - A Rapid, Sensitive Mass Spect. Method for... Biochem. and Biophys. Res. Comm., 143, no. 1 (1986): 420-426, 1985 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Ionization Methods in Mass Spect... Advances in Mass Spect., (1985): 271-186 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Particle Bombardment (KeV) Mass Spect. of... Int. J. of Mass Spect. and Ion Proc., 87 (1978): 85-97, 1986 October 3 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Cf Plasma Desorption Fourier Transform Mass... Int. J. of Mass Spect. and Ion Proc., 87 (1978): 305-313, 1986 November 24 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Biomedical and Environmental Mass Spect... Biomed. and Env. Mass Spect., 14 (1987): 295-299, 1987 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Ion Retardation and Collision-Induced Dissociation in... Anal. Chem., 60 (1988): 1323-1329, 1987 August 13 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Quantification of the Sulfates of 16-Hydroxy... Steroids, 50 (1987): 4-6 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Mass Spect. Characterization of Microscale Enzyme... Methods in Protein Sequence Analysis, (1986): 483-492, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Limits for the Use of CholestraU) and... Biomed. and Environ. Mass Spect., 17 (1988): 463-470, 1988 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Particle Bombardment (KeV) Mass Spectra of a... Int. J. of Mass Spect. and Ion Proc., 87 (1989): 95-109, 1988 March 25 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Studies of Gaseous Ionic Equilibria in... Advances in Mass Spect., 5: 226-228, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Manuscripts, 1966-1980; 2; 5.28 Cubic Feet
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - ASMS Abstracts, Chemical Ionization Mass Spectrometry (CIMS), of... M. Rennekamp, J. Shabanowitz, D.V. Bowen, F.H. Field, H. Geishinowitz, M. Meot-Ner, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Analysis of Lithium Using a Commercial... J.R. Lloyd and F.H. Field, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Analysis of Lithium Using a Commercial... J.R. Lloyd and F.H. Field, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Application of Transition State Theory to Ion... H. Gershinowitz, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Association and Solivation Reactions of... M. Meot-Ner and F.H. Field, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Benzyl Alcohol - High Levels Found in Plasma of... A. Bushra D. Cowburn, L. Craig, H. Kac, El Stoner, D. Bowen, F. Field, M. Rennekamp, J. Sullivan, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - CIMS. F.H. Field, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - CIMS. IV. Aeromatic Hydrocarbons, M.S.B. Munson and F.H. Field, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - CIMS. XII. Alcohols, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - CIMS. VIII. Alkenes and Alkynes, F.H. Field, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - CIMS. VIII. Alkenes and Alkynes, F.H. Field, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chemical Ionization Mass Spectrometry (CIMS). IV. Aeromatic Hydrocarbons, M.S.B. Munson and F.H. Field, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - CIMS. V. Cycloparaffins, F.H. Field and M.S.B. Munson, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - CIMS. VI. Cycloheptatriene and Norbornadieve, F.H. Field, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chemical Ionization Mass Spectrometry (CIMS). XIX. Determination of 15n... C.V. Lundeen, A.S. Viscomi, F.H. Field, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - CIMS. XVIII. Effect of Acid Identity on... W.A. Laurie and F.H. Field, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - CIMS. XVII. Effect of Pressure on the Decomposition of... W.A. Laurie and F.H. Field, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - CIMS. XX. Energy Effects and Decomposition Kinetics... M. Meot-Ner and F.H. Field, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - CIMS. II. Esters, M.S.B. Munson and F.H. Field, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chemical Ionization Mass Spectrometry (CIMS). I. General Introduction, M.S.B. Munson and F.H. Field, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)